http://models.com/company/privacy.html

Login to continue
Facebook
Twitter
or
Forgot your password?
Not a Member? Register Here
Not a member yet?
Register if you are a:
Model, Photographer, Stylist, Makeup or Hair Stylist, Casting Director, Agent, Magazine, PR or Ad agency, Production Company, Brand or just a Fan!
Register it's free »
×
MODELS.COM PRIVACY POLICY
OUR COMMITTMENT TO PRIVACY
Models.com and the Privacy of Visitors and Members
Internet user privacy and confidentiality is of the utmost importance to Models.com. Models.com’s reputation and integrity is directly related to how we serve Models.com’s Web site’s users and members.
Please find below a description of how Models.com strives to protect your privacy.
Models.com has a long-standing policy of privacy protection in place with opt-in defaults, for example requiring explicit consent for Models.com's email newsletter sign up (instead of a pre-set signup that has to be opted-out of), and a policy of only asking for the minimum possible amount of private data for the purposes of delivering Models.com services to members. Models.com only requests information that has a clear justification for its use in delivering Models.com services or is a legal or contractual requirement.
Whenever possible Models.com limits the usage of individual tracking by third parties, for example but not limited to, by using Google Analytics's ip address anonymizing feature, or by implementing social sharing buttons without external tracking, or by carefully evaluating the privacy protections of third parties services Models.com uses.
Protecting children
Models.com membership is exclusively geared toward individuals who are 13 years old and older. Models.com will not knowingly collect or use personal identifiable information from children younger than 13. Individuals between 13 and 18 should consult with their parents or guardians about the use of the site for their benefit, and are required to have their consent before using the site.
The Information We Collect
This notice applies to all information collected or submitted on the Models.com website or any of its services. On some pages, you can order products, sign up for membership, make requests, and register to receive materials. The types of personal information collected at these pages are:
Required personal information: this information is needed to verify your registration and acceptance of the Terms of Services, to provide the services you are registering for, and for account administration purposes such as lost password recovery.
Name
Date of Birth
Email
Professional role or interest (onboarding information needed to provide the correct type of membership service depending on your interests)
Optional personal information: this information may be required to provide a service you requested (such as a scouting portfolio, Pro membership or Models.com page):
Gender
City
State
Zip
Address
Phone number
Credit/Debit Card Information
Personal statistics (for model portfolios)
Photos (for model portfolios or Models.com pages)
Occupation and Interest
Other forms of electronic address (Web site, social media, etc.)
On some pages, you can submit information about other people. For example, if you order a gift online or send an email to someone from the Models.com Web site and want it sent directly to the recipient, you will need to submit the recipient’s address. In this circumstance, the types of personal information collected are:
Name
Address
Phone Number
Email address
When you create your Models.com account, and authenticate with a third-party service (like Twitter, Instagram, Facebook or Google), or if at a later time you link your Models.com account to one of these third party services, we may collect, store, and periodically update information associated with that third-party account, such as your lists of friends or followers but only after asking you for explicit permission for each type of information and only if that information is useful to deliver a service on Models.com you requested. When using a third-party service to login or register on Models.com you will only be asked for the minimum required permissions to fulfill that request, such as your third-party account basic information and authorization to use that third party account with your Models.com account. Sharing this information is not a requirement to use Models.com and is only requested if it fulfills a specific function of your Models.com membership that you explicitly decided and consented to use, if a function on Models.com requires additional permissions to access more of your personal information such as connecting you with friends on Models.com from other third party services, you will have to give your explicit consent to these additional permissions. We will never publish on your behalf through your third-party account without your explicit consent.
How we use the information we collect
Other than for the explicit purposes of fulfilling a service such as when you make a payment for a Models.com service and your personal information is used to verify and process your payment information, or in the case of the sale of a substantial portion of Models.com's assets or the sale of Models.com to a third party, Models.com never releases personal identifiable information about you to any third party without your initial prior approval. If we do release your information to a third party, for example to sign you up for a third party service provided through Models.com that you have specifically requested, a link to the third party’s privacy notice and terms of service will be displayed at the time you are offered the option to release this information.
BUT please note that Models.com may disclose user information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) Models.com’s rights or property, other Models.com users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. Models.com may disclose user information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.
We use the information you provide about someone else or yourself when placing an order or signing up for a service, only to ship the product and to confirm delivery or to provide the service. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete that order or provide that service. In cases in which we need to share the information with a third party to fulfill an order or provide a service, we will always inform you before sharing this information with these third parties, state how the information will be used by the third party by linking to their privacy statement and offer you the option to refuse to use the third party’s services or products.
We use return email addresses to answer the email we receive. Such addresses are not used for any other purpose and are not shared with outside parties.
We use your portfolio statistics information to enable autorized modeling agencies using Models.com's online scouting service to search through Models.com's database of members. This information is never tied to any personal identifying information about you during the search except for your first name, initial of last name, photographs and your general location (State + Country.) When an agency contacts you through Models.com's scouting system you can accept or decline to respond. If you do not respond the agency will not have access to any additional personal identifying information about you. If you accept, only the information you voluntarily disclose will be available to the agency.
You can choose to receive updates on Models.com’s new products and services at registration time. Information you submit on Models.com’s Web site will not be used for this purpose unless you fill out the registration form and select to receive these updates on Models.com’s new products and services.
We use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design Models.com’s Web site and to share with advertisers. For example, we may tell an advertiser that X number of individuals visited a certain area on Models.com’s Web site, or that Y number of men and Z number of women filled out Models.com’s registration form, but we would not disclose anything that could be used to identify those individuals.
Models.com collects information which is specific to how you use the Models.com Web site and the device and service you are connecting from. Models.com servers note details such as the server you are logged onto, the geographic location of the ISP you use, the type of browser you use, and your IP address. This information is obtained solely for the purpose of improving the delivery of services provided by Models.com, such as anonymized aggregate usage reports and ensuring the privacy and security of these services by analyzing Models.com users usage of the Models.com Web site and its services and in helping address technical problems or limitations of users's internet service, device or software or for legitimate business purposes in delivering services users have explicitly requested.
Finally, we never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described in this Privacy Policy.
Where we store user personal information
Models.com is based in and operating in the United States, its servers and all its data services, including hosting and backup of user data are stored in the United States, and may include backup data in multiple locations for redundancy and security purposes.
Outside data collecting services or data processors
Models.com uses various third parties to deliver its services to its users, some of which Models.com may have to share with some of your personal information for the purposes of delivering the service (for example to send you an email, or your payment information to process a credit card payment.) All usage of your personal information is stricly for the purposes of delivering the services you have requested.
Traffic tracking and analysis, hosting and backup services: Google Analytics and Google Cloud Platform
Social media login/registration/sharing/embedded content: Twitter
Social media login/registration/sharing/embedded content: Instagram
Social media login/registration/sharing: Facebook
Social media login/registration/sharing: Linkedin
Payment processing: Authorize.net
Payment processing: Paypal
Email delivery: Sparkpost
Email customer support system: Enchant
Fonts used on various Models.com pages: Fonts.com / Monotype
Media files processing storage, delivery and Web application firewall: StackPath/MaxCDN
Hosting and backup services: Amazon AWS
Web application firewall: Sucuri
Transfer of your personal information
Models.com does not sell or rent its members personal information with any third party, however If Models.com or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, then current personal information about Models.com members and their personal information will be one of the transferred assets.
How to withdraw your opt-in consent for contact and update or delete your personal information on Models.com
Models.com members can update their information by logging on to https://models.com/account using their username and password, and clicking on “edit account” or “portfolios” button to update their personal information as appropriate.
Opting-out of email announcements and marketing: Models.com members can select to opt-in or opt-out of receiving announcements and promotions from Models.com in two distinct ways:
– Upon sign up, by selecting the appropriate option during the registration process
– By logging in to https://models.com/account , clicking on “edit account” and selecting the appropriate option in the MODELS.com Email Newsletter Subscription section.
Please note that Models.com may still contact you for legitimate account administration purposes (such as but not limited to email verification, password recovery functions or expiration notices) as long as your account is not deleted, even if you have never opted-in or specifically opted-out of receiving email announcements and the Models.com newsletter.
Models.com members can delete their account on their account settings page at https://models.com/account/settings/ by clicking the "delete your account here" link at the bottom of the page and confirming their request.
At any time, you may later review or update ALL the personal information we have collected online from you by logging on to https://models.com/account and clicking “edit account” for your account information or “portfolios” for your Models.com portfolio information.
Our Commitment To Data Security
To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online, including using encryption site-wide by default, and encryption of sensitive user data such as passwords in Models.com's databases.
Advertisers on Models.com
All users accessing the Models.com Web site, and viewing advertisements on Models.com’s Web pages, retain complete anonymity where Models.com is concerned. As ads are delivered, Models.com does not acquire or collect any personal information about you. Your name, address, phone number, and email address all remain your private properties.
Tracking cookies
Models.com may use cookies to improve your Web browsing experience, to help distinguish users individidually for features that require users to be logged in to a Models.com account, or for features that are user selected. When you first access a Models.com Web page with or without an ad on it, Models.com or its advertising client may assign a unique random number to your computer browser – commonly known as a “cookie.” We do this to measure the popularity of the different sections of the site, and to understand the way a user responds to the ads we deliver. For example, this number lets us keep track of how many times you view an ad we distribute or which articles on the site are more popular. Likewise, the cookie can help make sure you do not see the same ad over and over and can also help us improve the Models.com Web site content and features based on users’s actual usage of the site – thus enhancing your online Web viewing experience. If you refuse a cookie, you can still use Models.com but your experience may differ from those individuals using cookies.
3rd Party Measurement Services
Often, advertisers will employ a third-party measurement service other than Models.com for tracking the performance of an ad program. In these instances, Models.com has no control over the information collected by the third party, and may not be held responsible for the actions of the third party measurement service where collected information is concerned. If you have questions regarding different third party measurement services and their respective methods of information collection, please contact support@models.com.
Disclosure
Models.com openly volunteers its practices of collecting information, its targeting capabilities, and its use of cookies. If you have any questions pertaining to this privacy policy and its contents, please direct your correspondence to support@models.com.
Models.com reserves the right to amend this Privacy Statement at any time without notice, and only the current Privacy Statement may be deemed effective. Regardless of later updates or changes to the Models.com Privacy Policy, we will never use the information you submit under the current Models.com Privacy Policy in a new way without first providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prevent that use.
This Privacy notice was last updated on May 25 2018.
Top
